Plastics Hall of Fame Records
Plastics Hall of Fame Records
1972-2018
The Plastics Academy, Inc.
3.0 linear ft
Records of the Plastics Academy related to the organization of the Plastics Hall of Fame containing correspondence, organizational notes, meeting minutes, member lists, press clippings, nomination forms, biographies, photographs, event information, induction ceremony programs and other materials related to the Plastics Hall of Fame.
3911508
Biographical History
The Plastics Hall of Fame is an industry educational organization founded to celebrate those "who, through dedication, work and accomplishment have contributed most significantly to the growth and success of the plastics industry." In October of 1972, Modern Plastics magazine in cooperation with The Society of the Plastics Industry (SPI) established the Plastics Hall of Fame. The first induction took place during the National Plastics Exposition and Conference held in Chicago from November 5 to 9, 1973. In 1974 the concept was expanded to include posthumous induction into the Hall of Fame to honor great contributors to the plastics industry. In 1976, Modern Plastics shifted responsibility for inducting members to the Society of the Plastics Industry (SPI) and after the 1982 event, the Plastics Academy Inc. (a tax exempt organization), was founded to manage the Hall of Fame nominations and inductions.
[Adapted from information given on the Plastics Academy website, http://www.plasticsacademy.org.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Plastics Hall of Fame Records contains correspondence, organizational notes, meeting minutes, member lists, press clippings, nomination forms, biographies, photographs, event information, induction ceremony programs and other materials related to the organization.
Administrative material contains documents regarding the operation of the organization including bylaws, nomination forms, procedural documents, membership lists, press releases, and relevant correspondence to and from the Plastics Hall of Fame. Also included are materials associated with the National Plastics Center & Museum, such as project estimates, floor plans, and exhibition drawings.
Nominations and inductions includes biographies and photographs of members of the Plastics Hall of Fame as well as materials relating to their nominations including nomination forms, letters of recommendation, articles, and additional biographical information. This series also contains materials relating to Plastics Hall of Fame induction ceremonies, such as notes and memos, event plans, program scripts, invitations, and event programs.
Most of the Photographs are formal shots (portrait photographs) of Hall of Fame inductees. The vast majority are prints or reproductions, but there are a few negatives and color slides.
Printed material contains newspaper and magazine articles relating to the organization and members of the Plastics Hall of Fame, as well as some issues of the Plastics Academy publications. Also included are studies and research reports relating to plastics in building construction.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Plastics; The Plastics Academy, Inc.; Plastics Hall of Fame.; Society of the Plastics Industry.; National Plastics Center & Museum.; Plastics industry and trade -- Technological innovations.; Plastics industry and trade -- United States.; Plastics industry and trade -- History.; Plastics -- Research.; Engineers.; Businessmen.; Inventors.; CD-ROMs.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Negatives (photographs); Newsletters.; Photographs.; Programs (documents); Reports.; Slides (photographs)
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Original collection, gift of National Plastics Center and Museum, 2010.
Later additions, gift of various individuals and organizations.
Inventory
- Administrative material
  - Bylaws, Plastics Academy, 23 Jan 1998 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, includes Plastics Hall of Fame, inductees, and members of the plastics industry (Box 1)
  - Elections and procedures, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Membership lists, Plastics Academy members and Plastics Hall of Fame inductees (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Museum and exhibitions, National Plastics Center and Museum, and Plastics Hall of Fame exhibitions (Box 1)
  - Press releases, 1976-1998 (Box 1)
  - Recommendations, administration (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1976-1998; includes introductory speeches, internal and external communications, membership application, and a cd-r with images of trophies and medals (Box 2)
- Nominations and inductions
  - Biographies of hall of fame inductees, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Induction ceremony, 1976-1979; 2 folders; correspondence, scripts, financials, etc. relating to event planning, budget, guests, and speakers (Box 2)
  - Induction ceremony, 1982; 2 folders; correspondence, scripts, financials, etc. relating to event planning, budget, guests, and speakers (Box 2)
  - Induction ceremony, 1982; correspondence, scripts, financials, etc. relating to event planning, budget, guests, and speakers (Box 3)
  - Induction ceremony programs, 1973; 1976,; 1979,; 1982,; 1986-1988,; 1991,; 1993-1994,; 1996-1997,; 1999-2000,; 2003,; 2005-2006,; 2008-2009,; 2011-2012,; 2014-2015,; 2018; 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Nomination materials, forms, schedules, deadlines (Box 4)
  - Nominations, 1972-1973; 1976,; 1979,; 1982; forms, letters of recommendation, biographies, etc.; 7 folders (Box 4)
  - Nominations, 1993-1998; forms, letters of recommendation, biographies, etc.; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Nominations, posthumous, correspondence, forms, etc. (Box 5)
- Photographs
  - Correspondence about (Box 5)
    These had already been separated from the photographs to which they refer when the collection was received.
  - Bill Cruse, India Trip, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Hall of Fame inductees, plast_hof_001; digital files, tif and jpg format; file listing; prints with filenames on reverse; CD-ROM (Box 5)
  - Hall of Fame inductees, A-G, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Hall of Fame inductees, H-W, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, includes group shots, photos of inductees receiving award, packet of photos from Russia (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, unidentified (Box 6)
  - Slides and negatives, some identified, some not (Box 6)
- Printed material
  - Clippings about Hall of Fame, 1972-2009 (Box 6)
  - Clippings about people (Box 6)
  - Clippings, miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Publications, issues of Plastics Academy News, Hall of Fame Newsletter (Box 6)
  - Reports, miscellaneous (Box 6)
    SMANCA, Thermoplastic Duct (PVC) Construction Manual, (1974)
    ASHRAE Standard, Energy Conservation in New Building Design (1975)
  - Technical Report, Fire Research Project, includes slides; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, brochure, notecards, etc. (Box 6)